在我出生的小镇上
In the little village where I was born,
人们过着悠闲的生活
life moved at a slower pace...
不过富翁都喜欢这样的生活
yet felt all the richer for it.
在那里  我的两个叔叔因为厨艺精湛
There, my two uncles were known far and wide
而声名远扬
for their delicious cooking.
他们只用最新鲜的药草和香料
They seasoned their zesty chicken
给他们的美味炸鸡调味
using only the freshest herbs and spices.
人们将他们称之为"炸鸡兄弟"
People called them "Los Pollos Hermanos"--the Chicken Brothers.
如今  我们传承叔叔们的手艺
Today, we carry on their tradition in a manner
并将之发扬光大
that would make my uncles proud.
精心的调制加上最完美的原料
The finest ingredients are brought together with loving care...
再慢慢烹炸到完美
then slow-cooked to perfection.
没错  在洛博罗炸鸡馆
Yes, the old ways are still best
祖传秘方依然是王道
at Los Pollos Hermanos.
不过不要光听我说
But don't take my word for it.
来尝一口  你便会知道
One taste and you'll know.
绝
命
毒
师
第三季
第九集
201.6磅
201.6.
老天  真是的
Jesus, seriously.
超标总比未达标强
Better over than under.
超了一磅半啊
Over by a pound and a half.
我以为你是个讲究精确的人呢
I thought you were all, like, precise.
无所谓了
Whatever.
我们把多余的弄出来保存到下周好了
We'll just save it out till next week.
别动了  就将就这样运出去
No. We ship it as-is.
当我们做慈善事业的吗
What are we, running a charity?
我们要把多余的取出来
we're gonna take it out.
别动了
Leave it.
一批货  一次出
One batch, one ship.
别把事情复杂化了
Stop complicating things.
你为什么要故意给他免费的冰毒
Why are you purposely giving him free meth?
这群贱人已经压榨我们够多的了
These bitches are bleeding us enough already.
你的酬金已经很多了
You are paid extraordinarily well.
-你为什么就不能满足呢  -的确是
- Why can't you just appreciate that? - Yeah, yeah, yeah, hey.
但我一直都在算账
Hey, I've been crunching numbers, all right?
你一直在算账吗
Oh, you've been crunching numbers?
对  我一直在算账
Yeah, I've been crunching numbers,
我不是数学家都算得清这笔账
and I don't gotta be a mathematician to figure out
你亏大了
that this deal you made is bullshit.
我们都赚到了
We both earn--
是  是啊  我知道
Yeah, yeah, yeah, I know...
每人一百五十万
a million and a half each.
哇哦
Whoop-de-doo.
他得到了什么
What's he getting?
他以4万每磅的价格批发
Say he's wholesaling at 40 large a pound.
这个价可能是有些高了
That's probably high.
你觉得我们的货卖这个价高了吗
High. Uh, what, for our stuff?
那价钱还只是据我所知
That's what I was getting.
好吧  听着  就算1磅要4万
All right, look, say he's getting 40 a pound.
好吗  3个月  每周200磅
All right? 200 pounds a week for three months.
3个月下来会怎样
And, like, what happens at the end of the three months?
听着  明白吗
Look, what-- whatever.
3个月  每周两百磅
200 pounds a week for three months.
那可是2400磅啊
That's 2400 pounds.
2400乘以4万可就是
2400 times 40,000 is--
我发誓  我已经算了不下十遍了
and I swear to God, I double-checked this, like, 10 times--
9600万美元
96 million dollars.
9600万美元啊
对吧  是9600万美元
All right? 96 million.
9600万才给我们300万
96 to our three.
简直糟糕透顶
That is messed up, yo. That is so messed up.
老实说  我都无法
Fairness-wise, I can't even--
杰西  你现在已经是百万富翁了
Jesse, you are now a millionaire,
你却还在抱怨
and you're complaining?
你以为你活在怎样的世界里
What world do you live in?
活在一个干了活  没有得到
One where the dudes who are actually doing all the work
应有酬劳的世界
ain't getting fisted.
你最近是怎么了
What is going on with you lately?
到底是怎么了
What's happened to you?
等下  我们就不能...
Hang on, can't we just--
我们得好好谈谈
Hey, we got to hash this out.
还有什么比钱更重要的吗
Hey, what's more important than money?
这种东西也好意思叫枕头
These things they laughingly call pillows,
就是给犯人用都嫌烂
I would not give them to prison inmates.
你想要我去再给你要一个吗
You want me to go ask for another?
不用了  记得提醒我从家里把他的带来就行了
No. Just remind me to bring his from home.
他们该多让他的腿活动活动
They're not moving his legs enough.
大家好
Hey, everybody.
你好  玛丽
Hi, Marie.
我能来看看他吗
Is it okay if-- if I visit?
恩
Yeah.
他气色不错
His color looks good.
格米  是你吗
Gomie, is that you?
老兄  是的  是我
Hey, buddy. Yeah, it's me.
真是你吗  格米
That's you, Gomie?
是的  汉克  我就在这
Yeah, Hank. I'm right here.
过来  靠近点
Come here. Closer.
怎么了
What is it?
靠近些
Closer.
混蛋
Asshole.
老兄  他把你给耍了
Man, he got you good.
是啊
Yeah, yeah.
我很高兴  你他妈还有幽默感
I'm glad to see you still have your twisted sense of humor.
老天
God.
看看这个
Hey, check this out.
我拿了点能让你心情好点的东西
I got something that'll make you feel better.
我一直在留意你的蓝色冰毒案
I've been keeping an eye on that blue meth of yours.
6-7周  没一点反应
Six, seven weeks, nothing.
然后突然间  到处都是
Then all of a sudden, boom. It's popping up everywhere.
看看新的地点
Look at the new locations.
德克萨斯  内华达
Texas, Nevada,
上面的法明顿
up in Farmington.
甚至在这儿
Even right here in town.
你知道吗  各地青少年已经
A teener here and there, you know,
完全是在街头交易了
strictly street-level amounts.
太疯狂了
Man, it's crazy.
你觉得我听了这个会心情好点吗
How exactly is that supposed to make me feel better?
因为你是对的
Because you were right.
你是唯一一个预料到这情况的人
You're the only one that saw this coming.
好吧  为我欢呼三声吧
Well, three cheers for me.
这东西他妈不起作用
This thing doesn't do a damned thing.
汉克  那个可能还在锁定状态
Hank, it's probably still on lock-out.
已经过了一个小时了  对吗
It's been an hour, right?
我这里很疼  我该吃点药了
I'm hurting here. I could use some meds.
好吧  我去给你找个医生过来
Okay. I'll go find somebody.
不许再说工作的事了
Hey, no more shop talk.
对不起
Sorry.
我没有预料到这一幕
I didn't see it coming.
什么
What?
你当然预料到了
Damn right you did.
没有  我什么都没料到
No, I didn't see shit.
总是差那么一点
Day late and a dollar short, as usual.
我之所以还活着是因为
The only reason I'm... even breathing...
我接到了一个警告电话
is I got a warning call.
警告电话  你什么意思
A warning call? What do you mean?
在他们袭击我的前一分钟
One minute before they attacked me,
有人打我手机告诉我要小心
somebody called my cell and told me to expect it.
用的话音加扰器  我听不出是谁
A voice scrambler. It could have been anybody.
玛丽把我的手机收起来了
Marie's got my phone somewhere,
如果你想要查那个来电的话
if you want to run the incoming.
应该得不到什么有价值的线索
Not that you're going to learn anything worth knowing.
我不明白  贩毒集团火拼
I don't get it. Cartel hit?
谁会打电话警告你呢
Who would have called to warn you?
我不知道
I don't know.
老天
Aw, Jesus.
不会吧  太痛了
Come on already.
坚持住
Hang on.
斯凯勒  这事与我无关
Skyler, I had nothing to do--
我们安全吗
Are we safe?
是的
Yes.
你安全吗
Are you safe?
当然
Absolutely.
杰西
Jesse?
你怎么样
What about you?
气色好多了
Face looks better.
一切进展如何
How's it all going?
想和我们聊聊吗
Anything you want to tell us about?
聊什么  我的趣味人生吗
What, like my interesting life?
混吃等死罢了
One day pretty much bleeds into the next.
我有工作了  很忙
Been working a lot. I got a job.
有工作是好事
Job is good.
在一家自助洗衣店
It's in a laundromat.
连锁集团性质的
It's totally corporate.
连锁自助洗衣店
Corporate laundromat.
感觉就是压抑  各种条条框框
It's, like, rigid. All kinds of red tape.
我老板是个混球  店主是个大混球
My boss is a dick. The owner? Super dick.
我都没见过店主  不够资格还是怎么的
I'm not worthy or whatever to meet him,
可我看得出来大家都怕他
but I guess everybody's scared of the dude.
店里都是些翻着死鱼眼的草包
The place is full of dead-eyed douche-bags,
工作时间超长
the hours suck,
没人清楚到底怎么回事
and nobody knows what's going on,
就这样
so...
听起来有点卡夫卡风格[压抑得让人做噩梦]
Sounds kind of Kafkaesque.
没错
Yeah.
完全的卡夫卡风格
Totally Kafkaesque.
绝对的
Majorly.
圣达菲的联邦检察长送的
Ooh, from the U.S. Attorney in Santa Fe.
真好
Very nice.
还有漂亮的郁金香和满天星
We've got all these nice tulips and baby's breath.
这是菊花吧  看起来像菊花
This is chrysanthemum. That looks like chrysanthemum.
汉克你看  多漂亮呀
Look at these Hank. Aren't they beautiful?
漂亮
Beautiful.
这个果篮好大个
Wow, look at the size of this basket.
里面好多吃的
It's got so many goodies in it.
看哪  巧克力脆皮饼干
Look, chocolate-covered pretzels
干酪条
and cheese sticks
还有风味橄榄
and some some fancy designer olives.
他不能吃干酪条
You had me at cheese sticks.
打赢我才给你吃  汉克
Mmm, you're going to have to fight me for those, Hank.
"泰德·贝内克携贝内克公司全体员工"
"Get well, and best wishes from Ted Beneke
"祝您早日康复"
and all the folks at Beneke Fabricators."
他准你这么长时间的假  还送东西
Wow, he gives you all this time off, and now this?
我也要去给他工作
Get me a job there.
我知道  他人超好
I know. He's great.
老板名人堂
Boss hall of fame.
我可没看见这里有克兰曼送的东西
I don't see anything here from Kleinman.
他们办事得有效率点才行
They're going to have to get on the stick.
今天感觉如何
How's everybody doing today?
很好  我们好极了
Good. We're good.
你呢
How are you?
我很好
I'm very good.
汉克
Hi, Hank.
做个小反应测验好吗
Just going to do a quick peripheral response, all right?
确认下康复程度
See where we're at.
关键时刻到了吗
Moment of truth, huh?
恩  可我不会这么叫
Yeah. I wouldn't call it that.
好了 我们开始吧
All right, let's just take a look here.
好
All right.
有感觉的话告诉我
All right, I want you to tell me if you can feel this.
这里呢
How about this?
好吧
Okay.
现在呢
How about now?
再划一下好吗
Do that one again, would you?
这里吗
Right there?
恩  我感觉到了  刺痛
Yeah, yeah, I feel it. A tingle.
好了  1到10级表示
Okay, on a scale of one to ten,
10表示你正常的触觉
ten being your normal level of feeling
1表示毫无感觉
and one bein no feeling at all.
说不好
Oh, I don't know.
4级
A four?
好了  4级  不错
Okay, four. Okay.
这里呢
And how about there?
有感觉  6级
Yeah. Um, a six.
好  很好
Okay, good.
这呢
And here?
有感觉  不那么明显
Yeah, still there. A little less.
-3级  -好
- A three. - Okay.
很好
All right, good.
谢谢配合  汉克  很好  非常好
Thank you very much, Hank. Good, good.
这算是好消息  对吧
So this is good news, right?
对  绝对是好消息
Oh, yeah, definitely.
看起来神经机能已经开始恢复了
It looks like some nerve function is returning.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank God.
好吧  他什么时候可以走路
All right, so when do we get him walking again?
玛丽  要达到预期固然很重要
Marie, it's important that we manage our expectations.
但即便是是数月的艰苦努力
We're talking about months of very hard work,
成功的几率也不是很大
and even then the odds, they're not great.
但你也不能确定
But you can't know for sure.
不能
No.
他什么时候开始理疗
When does he start physical therapy?
文件已经发到你的保险公司  优先处理
We've sent the paperwork to your insurance. It's high priority.
再过几天我们应该可以得到预授权
We should have pre-authorization the next few days.
最迟下周初
Certainly by early next week.
下周
Next week?
不行  太迟了
No, that's not going to do it.
我查过资料
I've looked into this.
理疗开始越早
The sooner physical therapy begins,
他康复的希望就越大
the better his chances are.
他需要每日理疗
He needs daily sessions.
不是吗
Isn't that right?
事实上
Well... Actually,
你们的健康计划治疗方案包含一项
your plan's treatment program
每周四次的理疗
covers four sessions a week.
事实上  她问的是医生
Actually, she asked the doctor.
每周四次是比较典型而且明智的计划
Plan-wise, four sessions a week is fairly typical.
你们的定点理疗师大部分还是不错的
And the therapists in your network are mostly fine.
大部分还不错  好吧  简直是太令人振奋了
Mostly fine? Okay. There's a ringing endorsement.
我想知道  如果能有更好的理疗师
Look, if Hank had more physical therapy,
做更多的理疗
with better therapists,
汉克能站起来的希望会更大的吧
wouldn't it be more likely he would walk?
玛丽  这种事情很难说
It's very hard to say, Marie.
健康计划治疗方案医学上完全可信
Is the health plan's way medically justifiable? Sure.
至于是不是最好...
Is it absolutely optimal?
别说了  管他妈的
You know, screw it.
我要先保证他得到最好的治疗
I'm going to make sure he gets what he needs,
赔偿的事以后再说
and they can just reimburse me later.
施拉德夫人  我非常理解你的感受
Mrs. Schrader, I get your frustration. Really, I do.
但我的建议是您最好不要脱离体系
But my best advice is stay in the network.
不要计划外开支
Don't go out of pocket.
理疗只是一个开始
Physical therapy is just the beginning.
你们还要请人护理  对家居设施进行改造
We're talking nursing care, modifications to your home,
进行职业疗法  购买医疗仪器
occupational therapy, medical equipment.
费用可能高达几十万美金
It could run into the hundreds of thousands of dollars.
那又怎样
So what?
你要我们在汉克的医护选择上妥协吗
We're just supposed to compromise on his care?
如果不遵照保险公司的规定就医
Well, if you don't follow the insurance company's procedures,
你们可能永远都拿不到赔偿
they may never pay you back.
我见过病人和家属徒劳等待赔偿金
I've seen patients and their families go bankrupt,
直到破产
waiting to be reimbursed.
你知道的最好的理疗师叫什么
Who is the best physical therapist that you know?
我可以为你引荐几位
I can give you some names.
但他们不太可能在健康计划中
But they're not likely to be on your plan.
让健康计划见鬼去吧
To hell with the plan.
他来了
Yeah, there he is.
你终于来了  我没等你先开始了
Finally. I went ahead and started without you.
姑娘们  这位是杰西君  给他来个全套
Ladies, this is Jesse-san. He's in for the full treatment.
把鞋脱了  躺下  去去角质
Kick off your shoes. Lay back. Exfoliate.
以后再说吧
Maybe later.
大师人呢
So, where's the maestro?
在外面停车吗
Was he out parking the mini-van?
怎么  我是他的跟屁虫吗
What do I look like, his shadow?
谁管他在哪儿呢
Who cares where he's at?
叫我来干什么
What am I doing here?
我本来想叫你俩一起来决定的
Well, I was going to have you two flip a coin,
既然大天才不肯赏脸
but since the genius can't be bothered,
你就走运了
today's your lucky day.
四下看看  小子  都是你的了
Look around, kiddo. It's all yours.
什么  这店吗
What? This?
没错  你现在是这家店的主人了
Yeah. You are now the owner of this fine establishment.
不要钱吗
For free?
不要钱  女士们快捂上耳朵
Free? Ladies, cover your ears.
不  哪能不要钱
No, not free.
听我说  这是一家信誉良好
Look, hey, this is a squeaky-clean,
盈利甚丰  至少是有潜力的
highly profitable-- at least potentially...
的本地机构
local institution,
很被商会以及商改局看好
looked upon with favor by the Chamber of Commerce. Better Business Bureau.
只要你31.2万  比抢还合算
At $312,000, it's a steal.
31.2万
312,000?
还没明白吗
Don't you get it?
外面看  这是一家美甲沙龙
On the outside, it's a nail salon, right?
里面看  就是你小子的洗钱圣地
On the inside, it's the best money laundry a growing boy could ask for.
等等  别走
Wait, wait.
等等
Wait.
女士们  谢谢  干得不错
Ladies, thank you. Thank you. Good job.
回来说话
Come back here.
坐下  回来
Sit. Come on.
容我解释一下
Humor me here for a second.
你明白你的钱是需要洗的  对吧
Now, you know you need to launder your money, right?
你明白个中原理的吧
Do you understand the basics of it?
我帮你安排  弄个幌子  洗钱之类
Placement, layering, integration?
我不会买什么美甲沙龙  算了吧
I ain't buying no damn nail salon, so just forget it.
所以你想蹲号子是吗
You want to stay out of jail, don't you?
你不想留着那些钱并逍遥快活吗
You want to keep your money and your freedom.
送你几个字
Because I got three little letters for you.
美国国税局[Internal Revenue Service]
IRS.
如果他们能逮到卡蓬[美国黑手党老大]  就能抓到你
If they can get Capone, they can get you.
看好了  假设这是你
Hey, look. Here's you, right?
粉红的  平克曼  对吧
Pink, Pinkman. Get it?
这是你的钱
Okay, here's your cash.
你在城外  在派对狂欢
You're out on the town. You're partying hearty.
跟辣妹们打得火热
You're knocking boots with the chickie babes.
看谁来了  税务局的
Oh, who's this? It's the tax man.
他注视着你
And he's looking at you.
他看到了什么
What does he see?
他看到一个年轻人  住着豪宅
He sees a young fellow with a big, fancy house,
钱财万贯  却没工作
unlimited cash supply, and no job.
他会从中得出什么结论
Now what is the conclusion the tax man makes?
我是个毒贩子
I'm a drug dealer.
错
Wrong.
错得离谱
Million times worse.
结论是  你逃税漏税
You're a tax cheat.
他们会怎么做  拿走每分钱
What do they do? They take every penny,
而你因为逃税去坐牢
and you go in the can for felony tax evasion.
知道错在哪吗
Ouch. What was your mistake?
错在你没洗钱
You didn't launder your money.
现在  把钱交给我
Now, you give me your money.
此为安排部署
That's called placement.
把那个小罐子递给我
Hand me that little thing bin.
假设这是美甲店
This is the nail salon, right?
我用你的赃款
I take your dirty money
用作美甲店运营的合法流动资金
and I slip it into the salon's nice, clean cash flow.
此为掩人耳目
That's called layering.
最后一着  洗钱完毕
Final step, integration.
美甲店的收入就流进老板的口袋
The revenues from the salon go to the owner.
也就是你  你那肮脏的毒品交易赃款
That's you. Your filthy drug money has been transformed
就变的合法了  还是税后所得
into nice, clean, taxable income,
通过理性投资  你的"事业"将蒸蒸日上
brought to you by a savvy investment in a thriving business.
所以你想要我买下这地方来交税
So you want me to buy this place so I can pay taxes.
我可是个罪犯
I'm a criminal, yo.
没错  可如果你想犯罪而不被逮
Yeah, and if you want to stay a criminal and not become, say, a convict,
那你得成熟点听取你律师的建议
then maybe you should grow up and listen to your lawyer.
是啊  这样你就能拿到那5%的钱了
Right, so you can get your 5%.
不  是17%
No, that's 17%.
我记得你说的是5
I heard you say 5.
当着我面说的
You said it right in front of me.
没错  不过是对你搭档说的
Yeah. That was for your partner.
资历较深者有优惠
It's privileges of seniority and all.
但你  跟以前一样  17%  已经很便宜了
But for you, it's the usual. 17%, and that's a bargain.
怎么了  你...  听着...
Hey, what, you-- Hey, listen to--
别这样  我在跟你谈你的将来
Come on, I'm talking to you about your future here.
要听从劝告呀
Listen to reason.
你连襟情况如何
How is your brother-in-law?
死不了
He'll live.
很好  我很高兴
Good. I'm glad.
沃尔特  你看上去很困惑
Walter, you seem troubled.
有什么能为你效劳吗
How can I help you?
我来见你是想...
I asked to see you in order to...
澄清事实
clear the air.
有些事
There are some issues
可能会引起我们之间的误会
that could cause a misunderstanding between us,
最明智的做法就是  打开天窗说亮话
and I think it's in our best interest to lay the cards on the table.
这样合作才是王道
That's the best way to do business.
我的连襟
My brother-in-law,
在他遇袭前
moments before he was attacked--
有人打电话警告他
someone called to warn him.
我想那位仁兄应该也在保护着我吧
I believe that same person was protecting me.
那两个杀手  想要杀的人该是我吧
Those two men, the assassins-- I believe I was their prime target,
出于某些原因  他们转移了目标
but that somehow they were steered away from me
去杀我的连襟
to my brother-in-law.
多亏了他  我才能活下来
Because of this intervention, I am alive.
而且我认为此仁兄的计划并不那么简单
And yet I think that this person was playing a much deeper game.
他打那通电话是希望双方交火
He made that phone call because he wanted a shootout,
而不是简单的暗杀
not a silent assassination.
一石二鸟  两败俱伤
In one stroke he bloodied both sides,
让墨美政府共同打击贩毒集团
set the American and Mexican governments against the cartel,
切断西南地区的冰毒供应
and cut off the supply of methamphetamine to the Southwest.
如果这人在国境的这边
If this man had his own source of product
有自己的产品生产渠道
on this side of the border...
那市场就全归他了
he would have the market to himself.
而利润将是...暴利
The rewards would be...enormous.
大家都是成年人
We're both adults.
我不可能装作不知道  你就是那位仁兄
I can't pretend I don't know that person is you.
这是毫无疑问的
I want there to be no confusion.
我知道我的命是你给的
I know I owe you my life.
而且我敬重你的谋略
And more than that, I respect the strategy.
换做是我  我也会这么做
In your position, I wouldn've done the same.
有件事一直困扰着我
One issue which troubles me--
我们三个月合同到期以后  我将何去何从
I don't know what happens when our three-month contract ends.
你想何去何从
What would you like to happen?
你知道我为什么入伙
You know why I do this.
我要保证家人的安全
I want security for my family.
我答应你
Then you have it.
3个月  300万
Three million for three months.
这是我们的协议
That was our agreement.
延长一年就是  1200万
Extended annually, twelve million a year.
一共就是1500万
Call it fifteen.
随时可供修改
Open-ended.
可以接受吗
Would that be agreeable?
之所以要谈论那些我们
Part of the reason we talk about what gets us riled up
生活中的不堪往事
in our daily lives,
是为了告诫所有人
is to help each other put a finger
不要再犯同样的错误
on what our relapse triggers might be,
将那些恶习扼杀在摇篮里
head off our disease before it comes back.
谁有话要说吗
So... anyone?
随便怎么抱怨都行
Free license to bitch and moan.
这机会可不是每天都有的
How often do you get that?
杰西  上次你说洗衣店的工作
Jesse, last time you seemed pretty down
让你情绪低落
about your job at the Laundromat.
我想问你
Let me ask you something.
如果有机会做你喜欢做的事
If you had the chance to do anything you wanted,
你想做什么
what would you do?
赚钱  赚很多很多钱
Make more green, man, a lot more.
先不谈钱  假设你什么都有了
Forget about money. Assume you have all you want.
我也不知道
I don't know.
可能我会做点东西
I guess I would make something.
比如
Like what?
不是什么重要的东西  但是...
Not that it even matters, but...
手工制作  我想
work with my hands, I guess.
建筑一类吗  就像...
Building things, like...
木工  或者砌砖之类的吗
carpentry or brick laying or something?
高中时候我上过职业技术课
I took this vo-tech class in high school,
木材加工
wood working.
我上过很多这样的课
I took a lot of vo-tech classes
一堆垃圾
because it was just a big jerk off,
但有一次  我遇到一位老师
but this one time I had this teacher
好像叫... 派克老师
name of, uh... Mr. Pike.
我猜他年轻时
I guess he was, like, a Marine
可能是海军陆战队之类的
or something before he got old.
他有点耳背
He was hard of hearing.
我在他课上的作业是做一个木盒子
My project for his class was to make this wooden box,
就是个小的...
you know, like a small--
就是个...盒子
just like a-- like a box,
可以放东西的
you know, to put stuff in.
我只想几下做完了事
So I wanted to get the thing done just as fast as possible.
这学期剩下的课就可以全翘了
I figured I could cut classes for the rest of the semester,
只要我做了东西  他就不能给我不及格
and he couldn't flunk me as long as I, you know, made the thing.
所以几天我就做好了
So I finished it in a couple days.
它看上去很烂
It looked pretty lame,
但还能用
but it worked,
可以用来随便放点什么东西
you know, for putting stuff in or whatnot.
我把它拿给派克老师看  给我打成绩
So when I showed it to Mr. Pike for my grade,
他看着它说
he looked at it and said,
你就只有这种程度吗
"Is that the best you can do?"
一开始我想
At first I thought to myself,
废话  贱人
"Hell, yeah, bitch.
给老子个D  然后闭嘴
"Now give me a D and shut up
我就可以去和弟兄们嗑药去了
so I can go blaze one with my boys."
这里借代上面的D 不是指成绩 指的是Drug 毒品
我也说不清
I don't know.
也许是因为他说话的方式
Maybe it was the way he said it, but...
就好比
it was, like, he w--
他并没有说那东西做的烂透了
he wasn't exactly saying it sucked.
他只是在很真诚地问我
He was just asking me honestly,
"你真的就只有这种能耐吗"
"Is that all you got?"
出于某些原因  我也寻思着
And for some reason I thought to myself,
我当然可以做的更好
"Yeah, man, I can do better,"
所以我开始重做
so I started from scratch.
做了一个又一个
I made another, then another,
到学期末
and by the end of the semester,
我一共做了有5个盒子
by, like, box number five,
你们真该看看我做的那盒子
I had built this thing. You should've seen it.
我当时肯定是疯了
It was insane.
居然用秘鲁胡桃木来做外壳  镶的是斑木
I mean, I built it out of Peruvian Walnut with inlaid Zebrawood.
用钉子钉一起的  没用螺丝
It was fitted with pegs, no screws.
我用砂纸磨了几天  直到磨得像玻璃一样光滑
I sanded it for days until it was smooth as glass.
然后我又用桐油来磨
Then I rubbed all the wood
所以盒子看上去色泽深暗且浓艳
with tung oil so it was rich and dark.
还散发出特有的香味
It even smelled good.
把鼻子贴近去闻  吸一口那香气
You know, you put nose in it and breathed in,
简直堪称完美
it was-- It was perfect.
那盒子后来怎么样了
What happened to the box?
我把盒子给了我妈妈
I, um-- I gave it to my mom.
很不错
Nice.
你知道我要说什么  对吧
You know what I'm going to say, don't you?
亡羊补牢  为时不晚
It's never too late.
大学里有开设艺术合作社的课程
They have art co-ops that offer classes,
还有成人拓展教育项目
adult extension program at the university.
其实我并没把盒子给我妈妈
You know, I didn't give the box to my mom.
而是用盒子换了1盎司大麻
I traded it for an ounce of weed.
他是英雄  总不能拒绝给英雄付保险吧
He's a hero. You don't deny coverage to a hero.
他们会说他们不是在拒绝付保险
They'll say they're not denying coverage.
不不  这点上我是完全赞同你的
No, no, I'm agreeing with you,
但我和沃尔特是经历过的
but I went through all this with Walt.
会花光你所有的积蓄  然后怎么办
You'll burn through your savings, and then what?
你们不是也熬过来了吗
Well, you two managed, right?
你自己也说了
You said yourself
格雷琴他们的钱  也没能支付所有的开销
that Elliot and Gretchen's money didn't cover everything.
天  我得回去了
Jesus, I've got to get back.
什么  别啊
What? No.
别回去  你该休息一下
No, no, no, you should rest.
你进去好好洗个澡如何
Look, why don't you go in and take a long bath
我在床上放了些干净的床单
I put some fresh sheets on the bed.
万一他醒了  我想待在他身边
I want to be there in case he wakes up.
他们给他用的药  够他睡到早上
With all they're giving him, he'll sleep till morning.
嗨  斯凯
Hey, Sky.
你来这干嘛呢
Wha-- What are you doing here?
我顺便过来看看
Well, I just thought I'd stop by
来看看你还好吗
to see how you're holding up.
时机不对吗  还是...
Is this a bad time, or...
你好
Um-- Hi.
Hi.
玛丽  这位是泰德  我的老板
Uh, Marie, this is Ted, my boss.
你就是泰德
Oh, you're Ted.
常听他们说起你
I've heard so much about you.
谢谢你送来的礼品篮
Thank you for your gift basket.
真的很周到
That was really thoughtful.
真的很体贴  谢谢  泰德
It was. It was really nice. Thank you, Ted.
-是干酪条吧  -恩  干酪条
- Cheese sticks. - Cheese sticks.
不客气
Well, you're welcome.
你也知道我很关心斯凯勒
You know, we care about Skyler so much
也就自然而然地关心一下她的家人
that naturally that extends to the whole family.
你要进屋吗
Are you coming in?
当然  你该进屋坐坐
Oh, yeah, you should.
-不好意思  进来吧  谢谢  -好的
- I'm sorry. Come on in, Ted. Thanks. - Okay.
我们刚正在喝酒  你要来一杯吗
We were just having some wine. Would you like a glass?
不了  谢谢
No. No, thanks.
我刚正在回家的路上
I'm just on my way home.
我只是想...
I just thought I'd--
我真的筋疲力尽了  我得去洗个澡
You know, I--I am really beat. I think I'm going to take that bath.
很高兴见到你  泰德
It was nice to meet you, Ted,
再次感谢
and thank you again.
我也很高兴见到你  玛丽
Nice to meet you, too, Marie.
请代我问候一下你丈夫
Please give my best wishes to your husband.
我会的
I will.
谢谢你能过来看我
Thanks for stopping by,
不过事实上有点...
but it's actually not a--
时机不太合适  所以...
not the best time for a visit, so--
我们能谈谈吗
Can we just talk for a minute?
我理解你得和家人待在一起
I know you need to be with your family,
不过我已经几天没你的音讯了
but I haven't heard from you in days
-我留了言...  -我很抱歉
- I left messages-- - I'm so sorry.
你给我放了假  我真的应该...
You gave me all that time off, and I really should've--
我要说的不是这个
That's not my point.
我很关心你  就是这样
I-- I care about you. That's all.
泰德  我...
Ted, I--
汉克出的这档子事
It's just this whole thing with Hank
我们还惊魂未定
has been one non-stop horror show,
所以你也知道...
you know, so...
我只是想让你知道
Well, I-- I just want you to know
我是一直支持你的
that I'm here for you.
谢谢
Thank you.
但我真的需要你去...
Um, but I really do need you to...
好吧
Okay. Okay?
斯凯尔  你妹妹看到我来这...
Skyler, I've got to say your sister seeing me here--
我是说
I mean--
那又怎样
So what?
我离婚了  你也离婚了  怎么样了嘛
I'm divorced. You're divorced. So what?
我们迟些时候再说这个  好吗  泰德
Okay, let's talk about it later, Ted, okay?
能告诉我为什么要保密的理由吗
Is there some reason for secrecy I'm not getting?
-因为  -迟些再说  泰德  现在不合适
- Because-- - Later. Ted, not now.
斯凯勒  你只需要告诉我...
Skyler, just tell me--
你非要这样是不是
You really want to do this now?
你非要逼我立刻作决定是吗
Are you really going to make me do this right now?
你说得没错
Yeah, you're right.
-我...  -我真不该来
- I'm-- - Bad idea to come here.
泰德  我...
Ted, I'm--
我们过后再谈吧
I'll see you in a day or two.
办公室里谈
Back at the office.
随你所愿吧
Take as much time as you want.
难以置信  你竟然把房车碾碎了
I can't believe you had to crush the RV.
肯定相当郁闷
Must've been, like... depressing.
说真的  那损失的确很大
For real. That's a stone loss.
没人能比我更怀念房车
No one misses it more than me.
随时随地  想制毒就制毒
Free to cook anytime, anywhere.
没有定额  也没老板
No quotas, no one to answer to.
搞这种东西都搞出责任来了
What's the point of being an outlaw
还算哪门子罪犯
when you've got responsibilities?
达斯·维德[星战黑武士]也有责任
Darth Vader had responsibilities.
他对死星有责任
He was responsible for the Death Star.
一点也没错  那两个大贱人
True that. Two of them bitches.
我只是说说而已  故意唱唱反调
Just saying. Devil's advocate.
我现在还得交税了吗  这他妈搞什么啊
I've got to pay taxes now? What the hell's up with that?
完全糟糕透顶  简直压抑得让人做噩梦
That's messed up, yo. That's Kafkaesque.
-比去教堂还压抑  -没错
- Church. - Right.
我们重新来过
Let's kick it back into gear.
东山再起吧
Let's start slinging again.
开工吧
Let's do it.
人生苦短  这可是我一直说的
Life's too short. That's what I say.
是啊  哥几个  我们才不需要房车
Hell, yeah, bitches. We don't need no RV.
我们只需要自行车
All we need is a bicycle,
一点通乐  还要点苏打
some Drano, soda bottles,
不行  绝对不行
Nah, nah, nah, no shake 'n bake.
拜托  你的自尊哪去了
Where's your self-respect? Come on.
也许是不太风光
Yo, maybe it ain't top shelf,
但至少比没有强吧
but we could at least move it.
还是可以小搞一把
Still kind of dry out there.
我们可以上街卖
Let's-- It'll sell on the street.
谁告诉你我们要上街卖
Who says we sell on the street?
我也许找到了一个全新的市场
Maybe I know a whole new market.
也许我们只需要冰毒就够了
Maybe all we need is the meth.
产量多少
What's the yield?
产量  快点
The yield. Come on.
201.8磅
Uh... 201.8.
202.1磅
我发现了几张新面孔
I see a couple new faces.
有谁想做自我介绍吗
Anybody want to introduce themselves?
一个一个来
Don't all speak at once.
你先
Yeah.
我叫布兰登
So my name's Brandon.
好的  布兰登
Okay, Brandon.
你想和大家聊聊你自己吗
You want to tell us something about yourself?
好吧  我之所以来这
Well, why I'm here--
只有一个原因
it's just one thing.
因为冰毒
It's meth.
冰毒是噩梦
It's bad.
我曾经戒过几次
Thought I had it kicked a couple times, you know,
但是  天啊
but then... Jesus.
结果街上又流了新品种
This new version of it hit the streets and...
不会是蓝色的那种吧
Not that blue stuff.
抱歉  我忘了举手
Oh, sorry, I didn't raise my hand.
没关系  来这里就是为了交流
No, go ahead. This is what we do.
没错  就是蓝色那种
Yeah, exactly, the blue stuff.
你也试过吗
You had it too
是啊  老兄
Yeah, bro.
多希望我从来没碰过那玩意
I wish I never even heard of it.
那玩意真是太够劲了
It was like lighting my whole head on fire.
是啊  简直让你欲罢不能
Yeah, stuff will burn you down.
唯一觉得我还有希望的就是
Only reason I have a hope in hell
那东西后来消失了
is because it's long gone.
为你感到羞耻
That's the shame of it.
别这么说  老兄
Nah, come on, man. Don't tell me that.
我听说那东西又回来了
I hear it's back in town.
坚持住  哥们儿  坚持住
Stay strong, brother. Stay strong.
一切都会好的
It's gonna be okay.
我发誓  我要把这事儿告诉媒体
I swear to God, I'll do it. I will go to the press.
48小时也好  夜间新闻也好
I will go to 48 Hours. I will go to Nightline.
不过没关系
is a Nightline anymore. It doesn't matter.
他们一定会报道出来的
They will all take it, and they will run with it
因为他是个英雄
because he is a hero,
英雄不会在43岁时就坐上轮椅
and he is not going to be in a wheelchair at 43.
天啊
Jesus.
玛丽  我知道斯凯勒应该和你说过了
Marie, I know Skyler's already told you this,
如果你需要帮助的话
but if there's every anything that you need,
任何需要
anything at all...
能有你们两个真好
It's good to have you here. Both of you.
我只希望能尽量为你做点什么
I just wish there was... something more that we could do.
沃尔特
Walt?
我们可以帮他们付钱
We can always pay their bills.
拜托  那可要好几万
Please, it's tens of thousands of dollars.
我们有钱  绰绰有余
We have the money, more than enough.
-沃尔特挣来的  -斯凯勒
- Walt earned it. - Skyler.
我觉得不该瞒着玛丽
I think Marie should know the truth.
斯凯勒  我不这么认为
Skyler, I really don't think this is a good idea.
-我认为  -他赌博赢来的
- I think that-- - He earned it gambling.
沃尔特和我
Walt and I, uh--
我们最近有点矛盾  你也知道的
We've had our problems lately. You know that.
其实归根结底  就是一个钱字
And, uh... what it all came down to really was... money.
就这么简单
Pure and simple.
当沃尔特他被诊断出癌症时
When Walt was diagnosed, it, um--
整个人都变了
It changed him.
现在回想起来  我仍然无法理解
Looking back, I don't think I ever really understood
到底他都经历过什么
what it was that he was going through.
不仅仅是对死亡的恐惧
It was more than facing death.
而且想到自己快死了  却无法为妻儿
It was knowing that he was going to leave behind...
留下一分一文
nothing.
不管怎么说  也正因如此
And so that's how this all started. For better or worse,
他想要留一笔钱  所以
he wanted to provide, and so...
他用他的方式付清了所有的医疗费用
he paid his medical bills the only way he knew how.
我以为是埃利奥特和格雷琴付的
I thought that Elliot and Gretchen paid for your treatment.
是啊  我之前也这么以为
Yeah, I thought so, too,
但事实是  他没有拿他们一分钱
but the truth is he never took their money, not a dime.
他的自尊心不允许自己
He was too proud to take
接受别人的施舍
what he considered to be charity.
我说的没错吧
Isn't that right?
所以他把心思都放在了这上面...
So he put his mind do it and--
而且你也知道他这个人
Well, you know how Walt is.
总能想出办法
He's-- He's a problem solver,
他看了不少书
and he read books,
研究了很久之后
and he did a whole bunch of research,
他想出了一套
and he came up with...
方法
this system.
什么方法
A system?
21点算牌法
A system for counting cards in Blackjack.
什么意思  像《雨人》里那样吗
W-What do you mean, like Rain Man?
我也不是很明白
Well, I don't pretend to understand, you know, all the details,
但他相信
but he was convinced
只要你投入足够的赌本
that if you put enough money into it,
你就会
he'd have a, um, uh--
那叫什么来着
God, what is it?
统计学上的极限情况
A statistical edge?
对  统计学上的...
Yes, statistical--
-所以  -嗯  没错
- So - Right. ...um, yeah.
所以只要他一有空
So he-- Every spare minute,
就跑去赌
Walt was at some card table somewhere,
开始他是去赌场赌
and at first he went to the casinos,
但之后他意识到
but then he realized that--
意识到
...but then he realized
赌场会将你的赢钱记录上报给国税局
that the casinos report your winnings to the IRS,
如果上报的话
and if it gets reported,
可能会被家里人发现
your family might find out,
如果不想被发现的话
and if you do not want your family to find out,
就得去另一个地方赌
then you find another place to gamble,
比如地下非法赌场
like an illegal, backroom game.
还记得他之前总是玩失踪吗
You remember all those long walks that Walt used to take,
老是不在家的那些时候吗
all that time he used to spend away from home?
我想至少有几个月的时间
I guess for a couple months there you were...
你都过着这种双重生活  对吗
sort of leading a double life, weren't you?
天啊
Oh, my God.
天啊  你
Oh, my God, your--
你上次所谓的神游出走  是为了掩饰这个吗
your fugue state, was that some sort of cover?
不  不是的
No. No.
那个是真的  玛丽
He did not fake that, Marie.
他失踪的那晚
The night that Walt disappeared...
输了14000
he los$14,000.
那是他的养老金
It was his pension fund,
还有我们的存款
our savings,
基本上可以说是倾家荡产了
basically every last dime we had to our name, gone.
所以他无法接受
He couldn't live with it.
死的心都有了
He was suicidal.
但你要知道
But you have to try to understand
他一离开医院
that as soon as he got out of the hospital,
马上就又回去赌了
he went right back to gambling.
简直是无法自拔
I mean, that's how deep this went.
你怎么能这样对她  沃尔特
How could you do that to her, Walt?
我
I, um--
不过  他想出的这套
Anyway, this system of his...
算牌方法最终成功了
he finally got it to work.
所以我想说的是
So all this is to say
我们有钱
we have the money.
虽已不再赌博
No more gambling.
但我们不差钱
But we have the money.
有多少
How... much money?
沃尔特
Walt?
这个...
Well, uh--
大概7位数的钱吧
It's in the seven figures.
我的天
Oh, God. Holy Mary, Mother of God.
怎么说呢
What can I say?
我在这方面是行家
I did very well.
玛丽
Marie...
你就用我们的钱
you will take our money.
来治疗汉克
Use it to take care of Hank.
拜托了  玛丽  让我们来帮忙吧
Please. Marie, let us help.
你儿子知道这事吗
Does Walt, Jr. Know about this?
当然不知道
Absolutely not,
一定要瞒着他
and I need to keep it that away,
还有汉克  好吗
and Hank-- okay--
汉克已经有太多烦心事了
Hank's got enough on his mind right now,
-所以你能帮我保密吗  -当然
- so can we just please keep this between us? - Yeah. Yeah, I--
我
Yeah, I--
我需要出去透透气
I just-- I need to--
好吧
Yeah, okay.
我们等下再说这个
We'll talk about it later.
你怎么想到这个的
How did you come up with that?
我是说
I mean, where--
亏你想得出来
where did you possibly--
和你学的
I learned from the best.
我的直觉告诉我
Somehow something tells me
汉克的事和你脱不了干系
that Hank is here because of you.
这可不是你能瞒混过关的
And I'm not forgetting that.